This is the Realm of Magic.
这里是魔法王国。
It's called so because magic is a natural part of people's life here.
之所以这么叫是因为魔法 是这里人们生活中很自然的一部分。
They can fly with a broom,
他们可以用扫帚飞,
levitate heavy objects,
悬浮重物,
or even make something out of thin air.
或者凭空制造什么东西。
In this world, people can use magic at will,
在这个世界上, 人们可以随意使用魔法,
and magic has become a regular part in their daily life.
魔法变成了 成为他们日常生活中的常规部分。
People believe that their magic is a gift given by god.
人们都这么认为 他们的魔法是上帝赐予的礼物。
And one's level of magic can even determine their social status.
还有一个人的魔法水平 甚至可以决定他们的社会地位。
In this world where dragons are flying in the sky,
在这个世界上，龙 在天空中飞翔,
there is a remote forest.
有一片遥远的森林。
And deep in the forest, there is a man
在森林深处，有一个人
who doesn't fit in with the rest of the world.
不合群的人 与世界其他地方格格不入。
There's nothing like cream puff after some exercise.
没什么比奶油泡芙更好的了 运动之后。
MASHLE: MAGIC AND MUSCLES
魔法和肌肉
My name is Regro Burnedead.
我的名字是烈火烧死。
My son and I live alone
我和我儿子独自生活
in this remote forest.
在这个偏远的森林里。
I'm a chic and elegant 75-year-old man.
我是一个时髦优雅的75岁老人。
REGRO BURNEDEAD
REGRO 被烧死了
I've done reckless things when I was young.
我做过不计后果的事 在我年轻的时候。
But when I get to this age, not much can bother me anymore.
但当我到了这个年纪, 没什么能再困扰我了。
If you ask me why,
如果你问我为什么,
it's my whole life's experience
这是我一生的经历
that taught me how to handle stress.
教会了我如何处理压力。
When there's stress…
有压力的时候。
Pop, I'm back.
爸爸，我回来了。
MASHLE BURNEDEAD
MASHLE 被烧死了
Why? Why do you have to break the door every time you come in, Mashle?
为什么? 你为什么要破门而入 每次你进来的时候，马歇尔？
Because I'm not sure whether I should push or pull.
因为我不确定 我该推还是该拉。
How many years have you been living here?
你在这里住了多少年了？
So I'm trying to find a solution.
所以我在想办法。
But you still broke it, didn't you?
但你还是把它弄坏了，不是吗？
Sorry, Pop. I'll fix it.
对不起，爸爸，我会修好的。
Never mind, since you've apologized.
算了，既然你已经道歉了。
He's always compliant after making mistakes.
他总是很听话 在犯错误之后。
You got it the wrong way!
你搞错了！
Strange. It won't fit.
奇怪，放不进去。
You got to turn it a little!
你得转一下！
Huh? What?
什么？
It won't work!
没用的！
I can't stop?
我停不下来？
Ah!
啊！
Sorry, Pop. I'll fix it.
对不起，爸爸，我会修好的。
Mashle, have you finished your training today?
Mashle 你说完了吗 你今天的训练？
Of course.
当然可以。
Well, Pop.
老爸。
I've been thinking about one thing.
我一直在想一件事。
Why do you make me keep working out?
你为什么让我一直锻炼？
You…
你..。
You are not like the others.
你和其他人不一样。
Unlike other people, you can't use magic at all.
不像其他人, 你根本不能使用魔法。
So at least…
所以至少..。
We'll talk about it some other time.
我们改天再谈。
I need to go out now.
我现在要出去。
Guard our house well.
保护好我们的房子。
Don't break the door again.
别再砸门了。
Yeah, I already know how to fix it.
是啊，我已经知道怎么修了。
Why don't you learn how to open it in the first place?
你为什么不学呢 怎么打开它？
Should I push or pull?
我应该推还是拉？
Pull! You pull!
拉! 你拉！
Anyway, I'm heading out.
不管怎样，我要走了。
I know I've told you this countless times, but still…
我知道我告诉过你 无数次了，但还是..。
Don't go to the city when I'm not around.
我不在的时候不要去城里。
I won't.
我不会的。
That's good. Good boy, Mashle.
很好，好孩子 Mashle。
I'll be on my way then.
那我走了。
Have a good trip.
旅途愉快。
Sorry, Pop.
对不起，爸爸。
I have to do this.
我必须这么做。
Magic.
魔法。
More magic.
更多的魔法。
People can still do many things with a swing of their hands.
人们仍然可以做很多事情 挥舞着双手。
I'll take seven of the special puff.
我要七个特制泡芙。
Welcome!
欢迎！
Heck!
见鬼！
I crushed them because I was too excited.
因为我太兴奋了，所以压扁了他们。
But coins don't usually bend when you squeeze them with bare hands.
但硬币通常不会弯曲 当你赤手空拳挤压它们的时候。
Sorry, I'll fix them right now.
对不起，我现在就去修。
Fix them…
治好他们。
Sorry about this.
不好意思。
Wait.
等等。
It's… terrifying!
太可怕了！
Sorry about the wait, here.
抱歉让你久等了。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
Hey, did you see that?
嘿，你看到了吗？
He doesn't have it on his face, or anywhere else.
他脸上没有表情, 或者其他任何地方。
No way! He really doesn't!
不可能，他真的不知道！
Unbelievable!
难以置信！
Sir, are you…
先生，你..。
Ah, nothing. Thanks for visiting.
没什么，谢谢你来看我。
This year's Divine Visionary
今年的神圣预言家
is Rayne Ames, a second year student
是 Rayne Ames 二年级学生
at the famous Easton Magic Academy.
在著名的伊斯顿魔术学院。
He has top performance at the academy this year.
他的表现很好 今年的最佳成绩。
Whoever awarded with this title
不管是谁授予了这个头衔
cannot only be elevated to the rank of the nobility,
不仅可以提升 到贵族阶级,
-but will also receive a scholarship of one billion Lond. -Oh, how nice.
但也将获得10亿英镑的奖学金。 哦，真好。
-Furthermore, they will have internal access -What a talented guy.
此外，他们将有内部访问 多么有才华的家伙。
-to the highest legal authority, -Compared with them,
- 最高法律权威, 与他们相比,
-the Bureau of Magic. -I can only waste my life
魔法局。 我只能浪费我的生命
-They are expected to have a bright future -in a place
他们被期望有一个光明的未来 在一个地方
-in the authorities. -like this.
在当局。 像这样。
Please… Please spare me.
求求你，饶了我吧。
I just nicked something.
我只是偷了点东西。
Are you kidding me?
你在开玩笑吗？
It's the scums like you who give me more work to do.
是像你这样的人渣 他们给了我更多的工作。
I'll have to make you regret what you did
我会让你后悔的
so that you won't cause me trouble again.
这样你就不会再给我惹麻烦了。
D-Don't! Please!
不要，求你了！
What? I'm busy.
什么? 我很忙。
What? There's an unmarked brat on the street?
什么? 有个没有标记的小屁孩 在大街上？
I wonder why those folks are so riled up.
我想知道那些人为什么这么生气。
Don't go to the city when I'm not around.
我不在的时候不要去城里。
Sorry, Pop.
对不起，爸爸。
But I didn't come here in vain.
但我不是白来的。
After all, I got the goblin cream puffs.
毕竟，我有地精奶油泡芙。
Yummy. Yummy. Yum…
好吃，好吃。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
Hey!
嘿！
Look what you've done!
看看你干的好事！
I'm an officer on duty here!
我是这里的值班警官！
VODKA 90% ABV I'm a magic police officer here
伏特加90% ABV 我是这里的魔法警察
to protect you ordinary people!
为了保护你们这些普通人！
Don't you have any gratitude?
你一点感激之情都没有吗？
I only got pennies every month for the work I do!
我只有几分钱 每个月为我的工作！
How about I take my stress out on you, kid?
我把压力释放出来怎么样 在你身上，孩子？
Do you want a cream puff?
你想吃奶油泡芙吗？
You sound pretty miserable.
你听起来很痛苦。
Are you pitying me? With a cream puff that's already chewed?
你在可怜我吗？ 用一个已经嚼过的奶油泡芙？
What do you mean by giving me a cream puff that's half eaten?
你什么意思 吃了一半的奶油泡芙？
Do you want an indirect kiss? Do you fancy me?
你想要一个间接吻吗？ 你喜欢我吗？
Are you looking for trouble with me?
你是想找我麻烦吗？
Do you know I represent the authorities?
你知道我代表当局吗？
And how are you going to pay for my uniform?
你打算怎么 付我制服的钱吗？
What?
什么？
I'm very sorry. I'll wash your clothes and return them to you.
非常抱歉，我会帮你洗衣服的 然后还给你。
I don't even have any clothes now!
我现在连衣服都没有了！
It's all your fault!
都是你的错！
What did you do to me? Huh?
你对我做了什么？
What is it, Terry?
怎么了 Terry？
Mr. Brad, this guy…
Brad 先生，这家伙..。
Don't yell for such petty things.
不要为这种小事大喊大叫。
But why are you half naked?
但你为什么半裸着？
BRAD COLEMAN
BRAD COLEMAN
No! It's this brat who…
不! 是这个小鬼..。
It's him?
是他吗？
The unmarked brat from the report?
报告里那个没有标记的小屁孩？
But how can he stuff himself with cream puff at a time like this?
但是他怎么能把自己塞进 在这种时候吃奶油泡芙？
Hey, you over there!
嘿，那边那个！
Please excuse my boy!
请原谅我的孩子！
This will be a bit of a hassle.
这会有点麻烦。
But now is my chance to hit something big.
但现在是我大展宏图的机会。
Go after them!
去追他们！
Idiot!
白痴！
I've told you not to go into the city.
我告诉过你不要进城。
How many times have I said that?
我说过多少次了？
I'm really sorry. It won't happen again.
我真的很抱歉，不会再发生了。
He looks upset and he's acknowledged his mistakes.
他看起来很沮丧 他承认了自己的错误。
I can't stay mad at him.
我不能一直生他的气。
Well then,
那么,
as a punishment,
作为惩罚,
you'll repeat this morning's training session.
你会重复 今天早上的训练课。
Okay.
好吧。
This cream puff is for you, Pop.
这个奶油泡芙是给你的，爸爸。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Please.
求你了。
Thanks, Pop.
谢谢，爸爸。
What a compliant kid.
真是个听话的孩子。
Aren't kids his age supposed to be more impulsive,
他这个年纪的孩子 应该是更冲动的,
have arguments and fights with parents,
和父母争吵吵架,
and gradually grow a stronger bond with their parents?
并逐渐形成一种更强的联系 和父母的关系？
But he's so obedient.
但他很听话。
I feel like I'm getting off too easy.
我觉得我太容易脱身了。
He's reached the age at which he'd want to leave home?
他已经到了这个年龄 他想离开家的地方吗？
For all this time, I stay away from people
一直以来，我都远离人群
and live a secluded life in the forest for Mashle.
过着隐居的生活 在森林里为了 Mashle。
But now, the magic police
但是现在，魔法警察
have learned his existence.
已经知道了他的存在。
I must find a way…
我必须找到一个方法..。
That is…
那是..。
Hey, old man. Where is that brat?
嘿，老家伙，那小子在哪儿？
I got trouble.
我有麻烦了。
The training only takes five minutes if I put my heart into it.
训练只需要五分钟 如果我全身心投入的话。
Okay, time to get back for more cream puffs.
好了，该回去了 再吃点奶油泡芙。
Cream as the cream in cream puff.
奶油就像奶油泡芙里的奶油。
Puff as the puff in cream puff.
就像奶油泡芙里的泡芙一样。
Cream puff as the cream puff in…
奶油泡芙..。
Should I push or pull?
我应该推还是拉？
Whatever.
随你怎么说。
Old man, you know what's up with that brat and you hid him here, right?
老头，你知道那小子怎么回事 你把他藏在这里，对吗？
Do you know what makes the magic
你知道是什么让魔法
in our world flourishing?
在我们的世界繁荣吗？
It's because we have cleaned the lowly blood
因为我们已经打扫干净了 卑微的血液
that has no magic power from our society.
没有来自我们社会的魔力。
That's a necessary sacrifice to keep our society running.
这是必要的牺牲 让我们的社会继续运转。
Let me be more specific.
让我说得更具体点。
People who can't use magic
不能使用魔法的人
don't deserve to survive.
不配活下去。
No, I should say they should never have been born.
不，我应该说 他们不应该出生。
Spit it out! Where is he?
快说! 他在哪儿？
I have no idea what you are talking about.
我不知道你在说什么。
Hiding unmarked people
藏匿无标记的人
is a serious crime, old man.
是很严重的罪行，老头。
Give him to me now.
马上把他给我。
I refuse.
我拒绝。
To be honest, if you cooperate and give that brat to me,
老实说，如果你合作的话 把那小子交给我,
I might let you off the hook.
我也许会放你一马。
I will… I'll never tell.
我永远不会说的。
Why can't you do something as simple as that?
你为什么不能做点什么 就这么简单？
I'm sorry.
对不起。
Your magic power is weak and you are so stupid.
你的魔力太弱了 你真是太蠢了。
We don't need a useless child like you
我们不需要像你这样没用的孩子
in our family.
在我们家族里。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
Hey! You screwed up something so simple.
嘿! 你把这么简单的事情都搞砸了。
You are so useless!
你真没用！
I… I'm sorry!
对... 对不起！
I can hardly find someone worse than you.
我几乎找不到比你更坏的人了。
I was never a bright kid when I was little.
我从来都不是个聪明的孩子 当我很小的时候。
As I grew older, I encountered failure after failure.
当我长大后，我遇到了 一次又一次的失败。
You failed again! You are fired!
你又失败了! 你被解雇了！
How can you even stand to be alive?
你怎么能忍受活着？
I would've killed myself if I were you.
如果我是你，我早就自杀了。
I was never needed by anyone.
从来没有人需要我。
And I've thought about taking my own life.
我也想过自杀。
I should just…
我应该..。
This child has no mark.
这孩子没有印记。
Did they abandon you because you have no mark?
他们抛弃你了吗 因为你没有目标？
We share the same fate.
我们命运相同。
At that moment,
在那一刻,
I felt needed for the first time in my life.
我觉得有人需要我 这是我人生中第一次。
I made a promise then,
我当时许下承诺,
that even though we are not biologically related,
即使 我们没有血缘关系,
even though the whole world rejects us,
即使全世界都拒绝我们,
I would still be his father.
我还是他的父亲。
Old man! Tell me where he is now!
老家伙! 告诉我他现在在哪里！
Run, Mashle!
快跑 Mashle！
You old fool!
你这个老傻瓜！
Hey! That means he must be somewhere close! Find him!
嘿! 这意味着 他一定就在附近! 找到他！
Yes!
太好了！
Run, Mashle!
快跑 Mashle！
Damn it! You old fool!
该死! 你这个老傻瓜！
Please let my voice reach him.
请让我的声音传达给他。
Shut up, you!
你闭嘴！
You have to live even if you are all alone in this world.
你必须活下去 即使你在这个世界上孤身一人。
For me, you are the only…
对我来说，你是唯一..。
Run! Run for your life! Mashle!
快跑! 快逃命! Mashle！
You stubborn old thing!
你这个顽固的老东西！
You'll regret this.
你会后悔的。
You brat! How dare you…
臭小子! 你怎么敢..。
Two uniforms in the same day.
同一天穿了两套制服。
Why? Why didn't you run away, Mashle?
为什么? 你为什么不逃跑呢，Mashle？
Because you are my family.
因为你是我的家人。
My only family.
我唯一的家人。
Pop, please forgive my stubbornness.
爸爸，请原谅我的固执。
But now…
但是现在..。
Go to hell, all of you.
你们都去死吧。
This is interesting.
真有意思。
You can't even use magic.
你甚至不能使用魔法。
How are you going to fight me?
你打算怎么跟我打？
Stupid brat. Mr. Brad used to work
白痴，布拉德先生以前工作过
in the Bureau of Magic's Security Force.
在魔法局的安全部队工作。
Even the regular Mages there are no match for him.
即使是那里的普通法师 不是他的对手。
It's a joke that a low-born brat without any magic power
一个出身卑微的小屁孩 没有任何魔力的小孩
thinks he has a chance against Mr. Brad.
认为他有机会对抗布拉德先生。
I can finish you within three second.
我可以在三秒钟内干掉你。
That's the magic he used to drive off the dragons
这就是他使用的魔法 把龙赶走
back in his days in the Security Force!
回到他在安全部队的日子！
I never thought I'd have the honor to witness it!
我从没想过 我有幸见证这一切！
Eat this! Nalcompas!
尝尝这个! Nalcompas！
Mashle!
Mashle！
That… That brat deflected Nalcompas
那个... 那个臭小子把纳尔帕斯引开了
with a single slap of hand?
只用一个巴掌？
Is it possible to stop magic attacks with a hand?
有没有可能 用一只手阻止魔法攻击？
I've driven off dragons with that magic.
我用那个魔法赶走过龙。
It's impossible!
这不可能！
Not bad, brat!
不错嘛，臭小子！
Let's see what you can do with this!
让我们看看你能做些什么！
The magic power is pouring out!
神奇的力量正在涌出！
Does he want to destroy this whole place?
他想毁了这整个地方吗？
Wait, Mr. Brad! You can't!
等等，布拉德先生，你不能这样！
Nalcompas Diagorus!
Nalcompas Diagorus！
Damn it!
该死的！
This guy…
这家伙..。
He reduced its momentum with his knees!
他用膝盖减小了它的动量！
How can he be so flexible?
他怎么能这么灵活？
Well then, take this!
那么，拿着这个！
He's even juggling it now!
他现在还在玩杂耍呢！
And he's dribbling it like a ball!
他像球一样运球！
He's making a fool of me!
他在愚弄我！
Pop, can I borrow your wand?
爸爸，我能借用一下你的魔杖吗？
What's he going to do?
他要做什么？
Does he know magic?
他会魔法吗？
It doesn't matter.
这不重要。
Some everyday magic
一些日常的魔法
won't lay a scratch on me.
不会对我造成伤害。
This is my first time
这是我的第一次
seeing someone use a wand like that.
看到有人那样使用魔杖。
I'll kill you if you hurt my family again.
如果你再伤害我的家人，我就杀了你。
I did make him exercise for self-defense purposes,
是我逼他的 出于自卫的目的,
but he could be that powerful?
但他有那么强大吗？
But no matter what, it's all over now.
但不管怎样，一切都结束了。
Even if we can drive off these people now, only more will…
就算我们现在能赶走这些人, 只有更多的人会..。
Interesting. Let's make a deal, mushroom head.
有意思，我们做个交易吧, 蘑菇头。
If you do what I ask,
如果你照我说的做,
I'll let you two slide.
我就不打扰你们了。
A deal?
交易？
In this country,
在这个国家,
they pick the best student every year to be worshipped as the one chosen by god.
他们每年都会选出最好的学生 作为被上帝选中的人被崇拜。
And they are called Divine Visionaries.
他们被称为神圣的远见者。
I want you to enroll in the magic academy and become a Divine Visionary.
我想让你进魔法学院 成为一个神圣的幻想家。
Simple, isn't it?
很简单，对吧？
If you get selected, it means you are accepted by god.
如果你被选中, 意思是你被上帝接受了。
And the society will accept you too.
社会也会接受你的。
I just want the money and the power that comes with this title.
我只想要钱 还有这个头衔带来的权力。
I'll help you on your way there, of course.
我会在路上帮你, 当然可以。
Don't listen to him, Mashle!
别听他的 Mashle！
He was our enemy just a minute ago!
一分钟前他还是我们的敌人！
You can be skeptical or whatever.
你可以持怀疑态度什么的。
But if you refuse, I'll keep hunting you for all your life.
但如果你拒绝, 我会追杀你一辈子。
And that means the whole country will be hunting you.
这意味着整个国家 都会追杀你。
You are a tough one, brat.
你真是个硬汉，小子。
But what about your old man?
那你老爸呢？
You'll be living in fear every day in your life.
你会生活在恐惧之中 你生命中的每一天。
You can't even set foot outside the house.
你甚至不能踏出家门一步。
Make your choice.
做出你的选择。
Do you want to be hunted for the rest of your life?
你想被追杀吗 一辈子吗？
Or do you want to give it all to change your fate?
还是你想全力以赴 来改变你的命运？
It's a deal.
一言为定。
Are you serious? It's a magic academy!
你开玩笑吧? 这可是魔法学院！
It's okay, Pop.
没事的，爸爸。
My willpower is twice as strong as that of others.
我的意志力是两倍 和其他人一样强大。
It's not about willpower!
这跟意志力无关！
Besides, I want to live a peaceful life with you.
而且，我也想 和你一起过平静的生活。
You are such a good kid.
你真是个好孩子。
I just want to live in peace with my family.
我只是想 和我的家人和平相处。
If this world doesn't even allow something like that,
如果这个世界不允许 这样的事情,
then I'll have to crush it
那我就得把它碾碎
with my fist.
用我的拳头。
NEXT EPISODE MASHLE BURNEDEAD AND THE MYSTERY MAZE
下集预告 MASHLE 被烧死了，还有神秘迷宫